我原以为加上政府的税后总额会达到20
I thought it would total to 20 after adding the government's tax.
MRP 是指最高零售价格
MRP means maximum retail price.
这个价格包括一切费用
This price includes everything.
好的，明白吗？
Okay, understood?
是的
Yes.
想象你喝了一瓶水
Imagine that you have drunk water
喝完之后你怎么扔瓶子
then how will you throw the bottle after that.
把它给我，先生
Give it to me, sir.
捏扁了这样扔
In this way.
就这样？
In this way?
它又恢复了原来的样子
It has regained its shape again.
这就是政府和你们这些人被欺骗的方式
This is the way the government and you people are being cheated.
这个瓶子会再次装满自来水供你饮用
This will again be filled with tap water for you to drink.
这是不应该发生的...-把它给我
For this should not happen... -give it to me.
把盖子捏扁
Press the cap in this way
然后放进去
and put it inside.
这样才是个废瓶子
This bottle is a waste now.
盖子拿不出来了
The cap cannot be removed now.
好吧
Okay.
这样，你就可以避免自己和他人喝到肮脏的水
By doing so you can save yourself and others from drinking dirty water.
太好了
Great.
国家可以通过两种方式进行改革
The country can change in two ways.
一种是自下而上的，来自底层，包括工人、农民和革命家
One from low level that includes, workers, farmers and revolutionists.
还有一种是自上而下的
And other from the top level.
行政服务官员、安全警察部队和国际税务局
IAS, IPS, and IRS.
从现在开始，你们都是有抱负的人，因为将来你们都有可能成为 IAS（印度公务员） 的一员
As of now, you are aspirants but you all will become an IAS in the future.
但为什么是你呢？
But why will you become?
为什么坐在你旁边的那个人考不上呢？
Why not the one who is sitting next to you will not become?
你有什么特别之处？
What is so special in you?
为什么偏偏是你能考上？
Why will you become and not the one sitting next to you?
先生，如果他学习好，那么他也能考上
Sir, if he studies well then he can also become.
如果只有一个名额怎么办？
What if there is only one seat?
那么考上的人会是我
Then I will become.
这就是我要问你的，为什么只有你能考上？
That is what I am asking you. Why only you will become?
你有什么特别之处？
What is that something special in you?
诚实
Honesty.
你不可能靠诚实通过 UPSC 考试
You cannot pass UPSC with honesty.
先生，我想要改变这个体制
Sir, my desire to change the system.
只有先进入体制才能改变体制
You can change the system only when you enter the system.
要先得到再谈欲望，坐下
First deserve and then desire. Sit down.
- 下一个-先生
- Next. - Sir.
- 是的-先生，积极应对
- Yes. - Sir, positive approach.
这个答案也不完整
This is incomplete.
这是世界上第二艰苦的考试，也是印度最古老的竞争性考试
This is world's second toughest and India's oldest competitive exam.
事情没那么简单
It is not that easy.
先生，奉献
Sir, dedication.
奉献精神，其他人还有答案吗
Dedication. Anyone else.
先生，为国家服务的激情
Sir, passion to serve the country.
先生
Sir.
我刚想起来，但是..
I just remembered but...
智力
Intelligence.
还应该有一个好老师
There should be a good teacher as well.
我们现在说的是有抱负的人
We are talking of aspirants now.
我们在谈论老师的时候会谈到这个问题
We shall talk about this when we are talking about teachers.
如果你需要一个比我更好的老师，那就多看看非学院吧
Study on Unacademy if you need a better teacher than me.
在那里你也能找到一个好老师，比我强点不多
There also you will find a teacher little better than me, not much.
即使你是一个优秀的老师
Even you are an excellent teacher.
这就是为什么我在非学院教书的原因
That is why I am teaching on Unacademy.
爱你，先生
Love you, sir.
我也爱你
Love you too.
好吧，让我们回到问题上来
Okay, let's go back to the question.
先生，需要勤奋学习
Sir, study day and night.
先生
Sir.
我刚想起来
I just remembered.
先生，耐心
Sir, patience.
耐心
Patience.
坚持不懈
Perseverance.
- 坚持不懈-好吧，还有呢？
Perseverance. Okay. What else?
- 你说什么?-奉献
- What did you say? - Dedication.
是的，是的..
Yes, yes...
耐心、毅力和奉献精神
Patience, perseverance, and dedication.
有这三种特质的人
The one who has these three strong qualities
才能进入IAS
will become an IAS.
乌龟
Tortoise.
你们知道乌龟吗？
Do you know about tortoise?
这不是一场普通的比赛，而是一场马拉松
It is not a normal race. It is a marathon.
兔子赢不了，这里谁赢了？
The rabbit does not win here. Who wins here?
乌龟
The tortoise.
做一只乌龟
Be a tortoise.
绝大多数的人会失去希望，崩溃并逃离考试
Maximum people lose hope, break down and run away from it.
在这个古老的选区
And in this Rajinder Nagar, old Rajinder Nagar
能够听到无数的情感故事
who will be able to hear countless stories of emotions
希望和失望
hopes and disappointments.
许多故事都是在这里开始和结束的
Many stories began and finished here.
但有些故事创造了历史
But some stories made history.
UPSC考试会榨干你的体力和精力
UPSC exam not only sucks you physically but mentally as well.
如果你第一次、第二次、第三次或第四次都没有成功
If you did not succeed in first, second, third or fourth attempt
那你六年的生命就白白浪费了
then six years of your life goes to waste.
自信是根深蒂固的
Self-confidence gets dug in the ground.
即使在学习了这么多之后，你仍然感到内心空虚
Even after studying so much you feel empty from inside.
没有人会看到你刻苦学习的一面
No one will see your hard work.
人们只会把你的失败做成奖章送给你
People will come and put the medal of failure
并评价你没有自知之明
and say that he was not sincere so did not clear.
你们当中99.9% 的人都考不上公务员
99.9% of people among you will not become an IAS.
我不是在开玩笑，而是陈述事实
I am not joking but stating the facts.
总共有120万考生
There are 12 lakh people
只有1.5万人能通过预考
who apply and out of that only 15,000 remain after prelims.
而在正式考试之后，只剩下3000个
And after mains only 3,000 are left.
面试结束后只剩1000人
And only 1,000 after the interview.
这我还是多说了
And that is the maximum number that I am saying.
这就意味着在这个教室里，你们中只有一个人，有可能会通过考试
That means from this classroom maybe one of you become IAS.
只是说可能，也可能一个都没有
Maybe, there is no guarantee.
你害怕了吗? 你可能觉得老师在打击我们的士气
Did you get scared? You are feeling that sir is demoralizing us.
他正在破坏我们的信心
He is breaking our confidence.
但即使这样你还是要继续准备,
But even then you continue your preparation,
你要刻苦学习，这会使你成为一个有能力通过UPSC考试的人
you'll study, put in your hard work and that makes you a worthy UPSC aspirant.
UPSC考试是艰难的
It is tough. UPSC exam is tough.
每个人都知道 UPSC 考试很难
Everyone knows that UPSC exam is tough.
为什么 UPSC 要被设计的如此艰难？
Why does UPSC take such a tough exam?
因为他们希望压力成为你的习惯
Because they want pressure to become your habit.
这种高强度的备考使压力成为你生活方式的一部分
This preparation makes pressure a part of your lifestyle.
UPSC 培训不是从 LBSNAA 开始，而是从这里开始，从准备开始
UPSC training does not begin from LBSNAA but from here, from preparation.
同学们，这是一项非常负责任的工作
It is a very responsible job, guys.
因为你必须处理世界上最大、最复杂的民主问题
Because you have to handle the world's biggest and complex democracy.
UPSC 会明智地选择你
UPSC will choose you wisely.
你必须抓住这种想法
You have to get hold of that thinking.
当英国人离开印度
When Britishers left India
他们离开后在印度发生的第二好的事情，就是UPSC
then the second best thing they left after railways was UPSC.
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
你正身处 UPSC 的麦加
You are in the Mecca of UPSC.
Rajinder Nagar选区
Old Rajinder Nagar.
如果你有时间，那么站在高处看一看
If you get time then look at it from height.
它是无限梦想的海洋
It is a sea of unlimited dreams.
我的乌龟们，跳进去，找到你们的梦想
My tortoises, jump into it and find out your dream.
不管 SK 先生说什么都能激励我
Whatever SK sir says really motivates me.
有时候这听起来很有趣
Sometimes it sounds funny.
你知道他在自行车上装了蓝色灯光吗？
Do you know he has put blue light on his bike?
- 所以人们才叫他蓝光-是的
- Okay, so that is why people call him blue light. - Yes.
哦..
Oh...
我已经告诉你加入 SK 先生的课时
I had told you to join SK sir's batch.
在你们学院我的选修课有个问题
There was a problem of my optional in your institute.
你可以在非学院选修
You can prepare for optional in Unacademy.
非学院有最好的教师可供选择
Unacademy has best teachers for optional.
非学院有我选修的科目吗？
Will I get my subject in Unacademy?
非学院有20多个科目
Unacademy has 20 plus subjects.
如果你时间充足的话，可以每天修10个
You can do daily 10 if you have the capacity.
我的天啊
Oh My God.
谁会给自行车装上蓝灯？
Who puts blue light on the bike?
政府已经禁止在汽车上装蓝灯了
Government has removed it from cars as well.
来吧，我们走
Come on let's go.
来吧
Come.
用这种方法按下盖子，把它放进去
Press the cap in this way and put it inside.
这个瓶子现在是废弃了，盖子现在不能打开了
This bottle is a waste now. The cap cannot be removed now.
你好，SK 先生
Hello SK sir.
先生
SK sir.
你好吗，我的兄弟？
How are you, my brother?
我很好
I am good.
你变帅了，兄弟
You have become handsome, brother.
坐
Sit.
- 你要喝茶吗?-好的，我来点
- Will you have tea? - Yes, I will order.
嘿，给我们弄两杯会议专用茶
Hey, get two meeting special tea for us.
会议
Meeting.
没问题的
We will get it. No problem.
你付钱了吗？
Did you pay for it?
没有，先生，我们也喝了两杯
No, sir. Even we had two.
他是我的学生，告诉我他们喝了两杯
He is my student and is telling me that they have also taken two.
你们报名参加非学院的比赛了吗？
Did you sign up in Unacademy Combat Gamified contest?
是的，先生，我们整个小组都报名了
Yes sir. Our entire group has done.
很好，很好，回去上课，祝你好运
Very good. Great. Get back to class. All the best.
好的，先生
Okay, sir.
你什么时候开始在这里教书的？
From when have you started teaching here?
叔叔开了一家为贫困人士服务的学院
Uncle opened an institute for underprivileged aspirants.
我说即使是我也会免费教三个小时
I said even I will teach three hours for free.
叔叔高兴，学生高兴，我也高兴
Uncle is happy, students are happy and so am I.
享受生活
Enjoying life.
我脸上有什么东西吗? 你在看什么？
Is something there? What are you staring at?
这是什么发型? 你为什么留头发？
What kind of hairstyle is this? Why have you grown your hair?
它给人一种高年级学生的感觉，否则学生们不会把我当回事
It gives a senior look. Otherwise students do not take me seriously.
这就是为什么？
That is why?
只为了让自己看起来像个学长？
How many times will you try to have senior look?
你这发型看起来像个傻瓜
You are looking a fool in this hairstyle.
- 别叫我傻瓜-为什么？
- Don't call me by that name. - Why?
否则，如果我评论你的头发，你会感觉很糟糕
Otherwise if I comment on your hair then you will feel bad.
随便说，我不觉得害羞
Say it. I don't feel shy here.
我不会注意你要说什么
I will not pay attention to what you will say.
嘿，伙计..
Hey, buddy...
格里
Guri
过去八个月你在哪里？
where were you for the last eight months?
我忙着工作
I was busy working.
我在脸书上看到你们创办的非政府组织
I read it on Facebook about NGO that you have started.
非政府组织
NGO.
在制鞋业中有许多黑钱
There is a lot of black money in the shoe business.
非政府组织并不意味着黑钱
NGO does not mean black money.
这就好比说所有的公务员都收过贿赂
It is same like saying that every IAS takes bribe.
有些人也很诚实
Some are honest as well.
你认为阿比拉什会受贿吗？
Do you think Abhilash would be taking bribe?
我怎么知道? 他不是我们地区的 DM
How do I know? He is not DM of my area.
他可能不是你所在地区的 DM
He may not be DM of your area
- 但他是你的朋友，所以出于好奇...-朋友？
- but he is your friend so out of curiosity... - Friend?
那个朋友已经六年没跟我说话了
That friend has talked to me for the last six years.
你还在生他的气
Your anger for him hasn't finished yet.
我再也见不到那个流氓的脸了
I would never see the face of that rascal.
好吧
Okay, okay...
你永远不会看到他的脸，倒是会看他的视频
You would never see his face but see his video full.
你在看什么? 你在看什么？
What were you looking at? What were you looking at?
格里，你在看什么？
Guri, what were you looking at?
试试看，大小合不合适
Look, whether the size is right or not.
合适吗？
Is it correct?
你一两年才见我一次，就不能买双名牌吗，伙计
You meet me once in a year or two. Get something branded, buddy.
你可以从工厂免费拿鞋
You get free things from your factory.
无赖，你是我的品牌大使
Rascal, you are my brand ambassador.
告诉我一件事
Tell me one thing.
你知道你的学生叫你 Neeli Batti (蓝色灯塔)吗
Do you know your students call you Neeli Batti (blue beacon)
- 别转移话题-是真的吗？
- Don't change the subject. - Is it true?
这是真的吗？
Is it true?
才不是真的，是误解
It is lies, misconception.
在最后一次考试中，没有人冒险改变选修科目
No one takes the risk of changing optional subject in the last attempt.
过去三天，我一直在向你解释同样的事情
For last three days I am explaining the same thing to you.
谁会在最后一刻更改选项？
Who changes the optional at the last minute?
我失败了三次，因为我选择了错误的科目
I failed three times because I chose the wrong subject.
我现在正在改变，已经决定了
I am changing now and that is decided.
我想学历史，而你现在把我搞糊涂了
I want to take history and you are confusing me now.
历史？
History?
你知道竞争有多激烈吗
Do you have an idea how much competition is there in
所有印地语中级学生都学过历史
All Hindi medium students have taken history.
你犯了一个又一个的错误
You are making mistakes one after another.
- 你决定改变了吗?-是的
- Have you decided to change? - Yes.
选择印地文学
Opt for Hindi Literature.
那里没有一个理科和英语的学生
None of the science and English students are there.
这是一个很好得分的科目
And it is a good scoring subject.
历史也像文学，但那是真实的故事，它们让我兴奋
History is also like literature but that is true stories and they excite me.
天才和傻瓜是两类人
Genius and fools are two categories of people
他们在最后一次尝试中改变了科目
who change their optional subject in the last attempt.
你也不是天才
And you are not a genius.
我知道，伙计
I know it, buddy.
这就是为什么我很紧张，想换个话题
That is why I am nervous and want to change the subject.
我不能重复同样的错误
I cannot repeat the same mistake.
嘿，来个火
Hey, light.
现在只有正确的选修才能保证我能通过最后一次尝试
Now only the correct optional can save my last attempt.
这就是我要说的
That is what I am saying.
从1991年到今天，所有的优胜者不是来自于酒吧广告就是来自于文学
All toppers since '91 till today have been either from Pub AD or from literature.
多读文学作品就能成功了
Finish it by taking literature.
这点不着
It is not working.
嘿，帮他点烟
Hey, light his cigarette.
如果这个科目如此重要，那么为什么其他有志之士还要选择其他科目呢？
If this subject is so important then why do other aspirants take other subjects?
为什么大家都不选？
Why don't everyone take this?
我可以告诉你..
I will tell you that...
不管是什么科目
Whatever subject
总能得到一些分数的，不要太担心
you take, a few marks here and there is going to happen. Don't worry so much.
- 冷静点-嘿，你安静点
- Chill. - Hey, keep quiet.
别担心，伙计
Do worry, buddy.
他不想通过UPSC考试
He does not want to pass UPSC and become an IAS.
这2-4分
These 2-4 marks
将带你从25平方英尺的房间，到2500平方英尺的大别墅
will take you from 25 square feet room to 2500 square feet bungalow.
你为什么选历史这样得分低的科目？
Why are you taking low scoring subject like History?
选择一个得分高的科目来增加你的机会
By taking a high scoring subject increase your chance.
到现在为止，你做的准备都是没有指导的
Till now you did preparation with job and without guidance.
现在你来这里是为了全面的准备
Now you have come here for full-fledged preparation.
所有有经验的人都在这里 Rajinder Nagar
All experienced ones are here in Rajinder Nagar.
这是你最后一次尝试，但是在他们面前你仍然是一个新人
It is your last attempt but you still are a fresher in front of them.
如果你不相信我
If you do not believe me
那就去问问别人，他们也会这么说
then go and ask anyone. They'll too say the same thing.
你不考 UPSC 吗？
Don't you want to do UPSC?
佩玛·日吉朱
Pema Rijiju.
他的整个家庭都是公务员
Pema Rijiju. His entire family is IAS.
他是谁? 他是 Rajinder Nagar 的甜心辛格
Who is he? He is Honey Singh of Rajinder Nagar.
别叫我甜心辛格
Don't call me Honey Singh.
就唱那首歌吧
Just sing that song.
你唱
You sing.
UPSC 只是一个借口
UPSC is just an excuse.
我必须面对自己
I have to face myself.
而且必须在说唱界大受欢迎
And have to be popular in rap.
- 这是你写的歌吗?-是的
- Is this yours? - Yes.
这太神奇了
This is amazing.
- 阿比拉什-你好
- Abhilash. - Hi.
他曾经和格里还有我一起上过大学
He used be in college with Guri and me.
他已经进行了三次正考和两次预考
He has given three attempts and two prelims.
现在他会做好充分的准备
Now he will give with good preparation.
告诉他我们三个在大学里是怎么叫的
Just tell him what we three were called in college.
我们三个曾经一起漫游，所以我们被称为三脚架
Three of us used to roam together so we were called tripod.
我们总是在一起
We were always together.
- 真的-三脚架，我们三个是平等的
- Really. - Tripod. Three of us were equal.
佩玛，我真的很喜欢甜心 · 辛格
Pema, I really like Honey Singh.
不管甜心 · 辛格做了什么，都不是真正的说唱
Whatever Honey Singh does is not the actual rap.
等着瞧吧，总有一天印度会有真正的说唱
Just wait and watch, one day there will be actual rap in India.
说唱是愤怒而不是女孩子的舞蹈
Rap is anger and not the dance of girls.
你为什么愤怒？
What are you angry about?
- SK.
给我一个节拍
Give me a beat.
“这里是 LBSNAA，要么通过，要么离开”
"This is LBSNAA, Crack it or leave it."
“这不是一首歌或说唱，但这是生活”
"This is not a song or rap but this is life."
“有时是艰难的，有时是轻松的”
"Sometimes it is tough and sometimes it is light."
“没有白天或黑夜，但每个人都很紧张”
"There is no day or night but everyone is tight."
“未来是光明的”
"Future is bright."
“有时候它是炸药，也是高度的沮丧”
"Sometimes it is dynamite. And height of frustration."
“ UPSC 野心家之战”
"Fight of UPSC aspirants."
或饶舌，但他们的生活
or rap but their life."
最后一次考试改科目？
Subject change in the last attempt?
以地理为例，每个人都在学地理
Take geography. Everyone is taking that.
选择那些容易得分的科目
Take that subject for which notes are easily available.
没错
That would be right.
“你必须每天承担学习的负担”
"You have to bear the the burden of studies every day."
“明星和嫉妒的人组成的军队”
"Army of stars and people who are jealous."
“忘掉睡眠，只是看看书”
"Forget the sleep and just look at the books."
“忘掉懒惰和邪恶的眼睛吧”
"Forget laziness and evil eyes."
“把它从根里拔出来”
"Pull it out from roots."
“不要抱有期望”
"Kill the expectations."
“来吧，白痴，杀了它”
"Come on idiot, kill it."
同样的科目，你也可以通过 UPCS
Same subject by which you can pass PCS as well.
想象一下，如果你没有通过 UPSC，那么你就有了 b 计划
Just imagine if you do not pass UPSC then you have plan B.
政治学让你也有机会成为一名政治家
Political science. You have scope to become a politician as well.
如果考不上公务员，父亲就不会让我嫁给你
Father will not get me married to you, if you do not become IAS.
那就继续乞求选票吧
Then keep begging for votes.
我叫你做什么你就做什么好吗？
Will you do whatever I ask you to do?
多放些辣酱
Put more spicy paste.
”自我怀疑，自我奋斗”
"Standing in self-doubts You fought hard yourself"
”你又追 AIR 了”
"You chased AIR Again again"
「读报成瘾」
"Consume newspapers Become Cigarette addict"
“梦想升级服务，但没有用”
"Dreaming UPSC But no use"
”因为你的朋友都在国外”
"As all your friends are abroad"
“但你还是被困在中途”
"But you still stuck in the midway."
“但是不要担心，因为有一天你会驾驶蓝色的灯塔”
"But don’t worry, because one day you will drive the blue beacon."
“相信我，就拿农业来说吧”
"Believe me and take agriculture."
没有人谈论农民
No one talks about farmers.
无论是在议会还是在路上
Neither in parliament nor on the road.
现在我只能希望你来讨论了
Now I just have hope from you dear.
嘿，这是一个叫做收藏家萨博的 WhatsApp 群组
Hey, this is a WhatsApp group named Collector Saab.
这里还有笔记、 PDF 格式的书籍和励志视频
This has notes, PDF of books and motivational videos as well.
如果你想问任何问题，那就毫不犹豫地在这里问
If you want to ask any question then put it here without any hesitation.
好吧
Okay.
就这样
Done.
听着，不要在这里发说唱
Listen. Stop sending rap here.
说唱也是一种激励
Even this is motivational.
励志的..
Motivational...
来吧
Come.
[电视新闻播放]
[news playing on TV]
什么事
Yes, tell me.
嘿，你在干什么? 我不是你的亲戚
Hey, what are you doing? I am not your relative.
阿姨，这只是出于对长辈的尊重
Aunty, it is just out of respect for elders.
不要以尊重为借口，进来吧，有什么事
Don't start telling me your problems under the pretext of respect.
阿姨，我可以在我房间听到这里的声音
Aunty, I could hear sounds in my room.
就是这个事
That is what I was saying.
发生了什么？
What has happened?
搞定他
Handle him.
告诉我，亲爱的
Tell me, dear.
叔叔，电视的音量很大，可以传到我的房间
Uncle, the volume of the TV is high and can be heard till my room.
所以我在学习的时候总是被打扰
So I am getting disturbed while studying.
请把它关掉
Please switch it off.
- 要我关掉吗?-是的
- Shall I switch it off? - Yes.
你真是个非常粗鲁的人！
You are a very rude person!
房子是我的，电视是我的，我在看新闻
The house is mine, TV is mine and I am watching news.
你有什么问题？
What is your problem?
告诉我一件事，你只关心时事吗？
Tell me one thing. Are you only bothered about current affairs?
当知识分子聚集在 Rajinder Nagar
When intellectuals meet in Rajinder Nagar
我也有一个建议，并希望说一些事情
I also have a suggestion and wish to say something.
如果不看电视，我该怎么办？
What will I do if not watch TV?
你想让我什么都不说吗？
Do you want me to say nothing?
叔叔，这将是一个每天的问题，然后
Uncle, this would be an everyday problem then.
我来这里学习
I have come to study here.
亲爱的
Dear
这就是为什么你的房租比较便宜
that is why the rent of your room is less.
你有这么多房间，所以你可以把电视移到别的房间
You have so many rooms so you can shift the TV in some other room.
如果我把它移到其他房间，其他人也会有噪音问题
Someone else will have problem with loud sound if I shift it to some other room.
别人将面临你现在的问题
That person will face problem.
你同意吗？
Are you okay with that?
是的，叔叔这样就好了
Yes, uncle. That would be fine.
很好？
Fine?
是的
Yes.
你会成为一个怎样的公务员？
What kind of an IAS officer you will become?
一个行政官员应该先为他人着想
An administrative officer should think about others before himself.
你太消极了
You are very negative.
孩子，过来和我坐在一起
Listen, dear. Come and sit with me.
他们都会收听新闻，你的准备工作也会做好
Both will listen news and your preparation will also be done.
你会在 GS 考试中得到满分，并且会为此感谢我
You will get full marks in GS and will thank me for that.
两年前，一个男孩住在你住的房间里
Two years back a boy used to stay in the room in which you are staying.
- 他很成功-怎么做到的？
He was successful. How?
他过去常坐在这里和我一起听新闻
He used to sit here and listen to news with me.
来，坐下来听听新闻
Come, sit and listen to the news.
- 来-拿着这个
-Come. -Take this.
我做了烤面包
I have made 'roti' (bread).
如果凉了，我不会再加热的
I will not reheat them if they get cold.
快点喝
Drink it fast.
阿姨也喝酒吗？
Even aunty drinks?
当然，毕竟她是旁遮普人
Of course. She is a Punjabi after all.
干杯
Cheers.
你想吃什么？
What will you have?
我不想喝酒
I don't want to drink.
喝一杯对你没什么害处，宝贝
Just one drink won't harm you, baby.
来吧，宝贝，像个运动员
Come on baby, be a sport.
你怎么能这么说? 我们是旁遮普人
How can you say that? We are Punjabi.
如果你是旁遮普人，那么你会喝掉整个酒吧吗？
If you area Punjabi then will you drink the entire bar?
我也是旁遮普人，我喝酒了吗？
I am also a Punjabi. Am I drinking?
小声点
Speak softly.
那个老头叫什么来着？
Who was that old man?
瓦利亚
Walia.
瓦利亚叔叔，他过去常说什么来着？
Walia uncle. What was it that he used to say?
我们是旁遮普人
We are Punjabis.
那些美好的日子
Those were great days.
那是一段美好的时光
That was a good time.
听着，我还没有告诉你我为什么来德里？
Listen, I did not tell you why have I come to Delhi?
你想开一个鞋子展会吗？
Do you want to open a showroom of shoes?
那个还早呢
There is still time for that.
我想见到你之后再告诉你
I thought I would tell you after meeting you.
现在就告诉我吧
Tell me now.
我要结婚了
I am getting married.
什么？
What?
我要结婚了
I am getting married.
嘿伙计
Hey, buddy.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
干杯干杯
Cheers. Cheers.
什么时候的事？
When did all this happen?
就在几天前
Just few days back.
很好
Very good.
当普拉加蒂通过了 UPCS，所有的男孩都会来评判你
When Pragati passed PCS then all boys used to judge you
那为什么普拉加蒂要嫁给你？
that why would Pragati marry you?
他们为什么要评判我? 他们中有人及格了吗？
Why would they judge me? Did anyone of them pass?
别生气，这只是个玩笑
Don't get offended. It was a joke.
你是我们组里第一个结婚的
You are the first one to get married in our group.
整个 UPSC 小组都会来参加婚礼
The entire UPSC gang will come for the wedding. The entire gang.
- 我会邀请阿比拉什-我不会邀请阿比拉什的
- I will invite Abhilash. - I am not inviting Abhilash.
那就不要邀请
Don't invite then.
- 所以只有 SK 和我应该来-是的
- So only SK and I should come. - Yes.
我会带上普拉加蒂和我们一起，她会感觉很糟糕
We will get Pragati along with us. She will feel bad.
房间空间很小，也没有多少酒
There is less space and alcohol in the room.
如果女孩来了，一定会拥挤不堪
And if the girl comes then it will get congested.
欢迎来到 Rajinder Nagar，兄弟
Welcome to Rajinder Nagar, brother.
好的，我会去接液体黄油的
Okay, I will come and get clarified butter.
嘿，出生在哈里亚纳邦的旁遮普人，你会喝掺有液体黄油的酒吗？
Hey Haryana born Punjabi, will you drink alcohol mixed with clarified butter?
嘿，妈妈特别为你送来了自制的纯液体黄油
Hey, mother has sent especially for you homemade pure clarified butter.
SK 说你已经变得非常虚弱
SK was saying that you have become very weak.
谁? SK? 他觉得整个国家都很脆弱
Who? SK? He feels the entire country is weak.
就是那儿，好的，晚上见
That is there. Okay will meet you in the evening.
好吧那晚上见
Okay, then see you in the evening.
[电台播放的新闻]
[news playing on Radio]
打扰了，桑迪普
Bother, Sandeep.
我是住在你隔壁房间的阿比拉什
I am Abhilash staying in the room next to you.
我也在为 UPSC 做准备
I am also preparing for UPSC.
我看得出来
I can see.
这是..
It's...
你为什么不在手机上听呢？
Why don't you listen to this on the mobile?
手机上的新闻越来越少，干扰越来越多
There is less of news and more of distraction in the mobile.
是的，正确
Yes, correct.
周围的有志之士说得对
The aspirants around are correct in saying
任何人都可以通过或不通过，但你一定会通过 UPSC 考试
that anyone else may pass or not but you will surely clear UPSC exam.
真了不起，你已经两次通过正考了
It is such a big thing that you have cleared mains twice.
如果我能得到一些指导..
If I get some guidance then...
我为什么要这么做？
Why would I do that?
如果你没通过，那么你会说我给了错误的指导
If you did not clear then you would say that I gave wrong guidance.
我会在这里创造我的未来，还是成为你的向导？
Will I make my future here or become your guide?
我只是想如果我可以讨论科目，教学大纲..
I just thought if I could discuss subjects, syllabus...
那些东西老师会告诉你，不然他们为什么要收费？
The coaching staff will tell. What are they taking fees for?
我还没报名呢
I haven't joined yet.
太好了！
Great!
你什么时候会报名？
When will you do that?
你真的想考上公务员吗？
Do you want to become IAS first?
你可以再晚点报名
You can join coaching later.
好吧
Fine.
[电台播放的新闻]
[news playing on Radio]
好吧，再见
Okay, bye.
不要太担心这个问题
Don't get so worried about the subject.
既然你已经来到这里，你一定会清楚的
Now that you have come here you will surely clear.
给你
Here.
尝一尝，然后告诉我味道如何
Taste and tell me how it is.
格里，你疯了吗？
Are you crazy, Guri?
请尝一点
Please taste some.
因为你，我们在大学里吃了那么多素食
Because of you we ate so much vegetarian food in college.
来吃吧，要不要给你一块腿肉？
Come on eat. Shall I give you leg piece?
格里，你疯了吗？
Have you gone crazy, Guri?
嘿... 好吧，那你可能会饿死
Hey... fine, then you may die of hunger.
我不会为你煮扁豆
I am not going to cook lentil for you.
太神奇了
Amazing.
我正在这个小厨房里做2公斤的鸡
I'm cooking 2kg chicken in this small kitchen.
太咸了
It is very salty.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
对我来说，所有的科目都是一样的
For me all subjects are the same.
我选什么科目都没问题
I could have taken anything.
你说呢，SK？
What do you say, SK?
- 你可以选择任何科目-任何科目
- You can take anything. - Anything.
但是我选择了普拉加蒂
But I took that option which Pragati took.
我以为因为这个，我就能和她说话了
I thought because of this I will be able to talk to her.
我们的关系变得更深了，兄弟，变得更深了
The matter got deepened, brother. It got deepened.
你的问题已经解决了，但我们正在讨论我的问题
Your matter is solved but we are discussing it for me.
我去那里干什么？
What am I there for?
我会让你更容易做出决定
I will make it easier for you to make a decision.
仔细听我说，舒舒服服地坐着
Listen to me carefully. Sit comfortably.
我坐得很舒服
I am sitting comfortably.
选择容易得分的
Choose the subject that is scoring
而且符合你教育背景的科目
and matches your educational background.
就是这样
That's it.
而且它应该与时事有关，这样它就可以帮助你在预备考试
And it should be related to current affairs so that it helps you in Prelims.
这应该对你的正考和面试有帮助
It should help you in the mains and interview.
选择那个科目
Choose that subject.
而且你不需要死记硬背
And you need not do mugging up.
不用死记硬背，就像他一样
No mugging. Just like him.
它应该是基于逻辑的
It should be logic-based.
学习材料应该能在地摊随处可见
Its study material should be easily available with the scrap seller.
因此，自学变得更加容易
So that self-learning becomes easier.
是的，你需要一个好老师
And yes you need a good teacher.
因为现在没有德罗那查里亚，没有人能成为阿尔琼
Because nowadays without Dronacharya no one can become Arjun.
你还记得... ？
Do you remember...?
拇指，祭品，还有《摩呵婆罗多》 ？
Thumb, sacrifice, and Mahabharata?
埃克拉瓦娅割破了拇指
Eklavaya had cut the thumb.
这是伊克洛维亚，不是阿尔琼
This was Eklavya and not Arjun.
真的吗? SK？
Really? SK?
是的
Yes.
没问题
No problem.
最后也是最重要的一点
Last and the most important point
这门学科的教学大纲不应过于宽泛
is that the syllabus of the subject should not be vast.
所以课程很快就结束了
So that the course finishes quickly.
然后我们享受派对
And then after that we enjoy and party.
这个科目对你来说是完美的，它具有所有这些特质
That subject is perfect for you which has all these qualities.
哪一个是完美的科目？
Which is that perfect subject?
这个我也要说吗? 你得自己决定
Will I have to tell that too? You have to decide that.
我现在更加困惑了
I have got more confused now.
为什么困惑，伙计？
What is the confusion, buddy?
冷静点伙计
Calm down, buddy.
你要成为什么样的公务员？
How will you become IAS like this?
连这个问题都解决不了，那么你将如何为这个国家做决定
He cannot decide on a subject then how will you take decision for the country.
解释给他听
Explain it to him.
无论他走到哪一个州，他都会使那个州失败
In whichever state he goes he will make that state a failure.
SK，告诉他我父亲在哈里亚纳邦有多少土地
SK, tell him how much land my father owns in Haryana.
10... 那叫什么
10... what is that called.
他拥有20英亩土地
He owns 20 acres.
他又买了10英亩
He has bought 10 more.
20英亩
20 acres.
我父亲在哈里亚纳邦拥有20英亩土地
My father owns 20 acres of land in Haryana.
整个村子的人都怕我父亲
The entire village is scared of my father.
一位来自昌迪加尔的公务员
An IAS officer came from Chandigarh.
他..
He...
什么？
What?
他一下子就把我爸吓得屁滚尿流
He scared the shit out of my dad in a flick of a moment.
这时我才明白，沙克蒂马安是个白痴傻瓜
I then understood that Shaktimaan is an idiot fool.
安静，瓦利亚叔叔会上楼来
Quiet. Walia uncle will come upstairs.
他是个白痴傻瓜
He is an idiot fool.
实际权力掌握在公务员手中
Actual power is in the hands of IAS.
那天我决定
That day I decided
如果你想出人头地，只会是公务员，混蛋
that if you become anything that would be only IAS, motherfucker.
当你经过殖民地的时候
And when you pass through the colony...
哈喽
Hello.
我在格里家
I am at Guri's place.
我是格里
I am Guri.
对不起，普拉加蒂
Sorry, Pragati.
我马上就到
I'll be there immediately.
我会去的
I'll be there.
哦，不！
Oh no!
别担心
Don't worry.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
阿比拉什，请听我写的两行诗
Abhilash, listen to the two lines that I have written.
我回来以后会听的
I will listen after I am back.
你听他说了那么多
You listened to him completely...
他的话你全听了，我的……
You listened to him completely and mine...
我在那些时刻发现了一些东西
I am finding something in those moments.
生活还在继续
Life is moving on.
我在想什么？
What am I thinking?
我写了些什么废话？
What nonsense have I written?
怎么了？
What happened?
你是在想选择 UPSC 是不是错误的决定？
Do you think you have taken wrong decision by opting for UPSC?
不是的，桑迪普
No, no Sandeep.
你为什么会有这种感觉？
Why did you feel this way?
你迷茫的脸庞正在破坏这美丽的星夜
Your confused face is spoiling this beautiful starry night.
桑迪普，我们生活在一个后现代主义社会
Sandeep, we are living in a post modernism society.
我们往往会感到困惑
We tend to be confused.
我只是有一点点困惑
I am just a little more.
这里是卖茶的瓦利亚叔叔
Here Walia uncle, the tea seller
家人常说
and family used to say
现在甚至朋友都开始说，我怎么才能成为公务员
and now even friends have started saying that how can I become IAS in this way.
让我先通过 UPSC
Let me clear UPSC first.
现在每个人都在评判我
Every person is judging me at present.
你才来了一个星期，就受不了这一切
It has just been a week you are here and you cannot bear all this.
那你怎么能考上公务员呢？
How will you become IAS in this way?
我只是在开玩笑
I am just joking.
什么... ？
What...?
什么是官僚？
What is Bureaucrat?
什么？
What?
什么是官僚？
What is Bureaucrat?
官僚？
Bureaucrat?
官僚主义？
Bureaucracy?
公务员是公众的公仆
An IAS is a servant of the public.
当你成为了公务员
When you will become
那你就得无私地为这些人服务
then you will have to serve these people selflessly.
这是事实
This is a fact.
但是很多人考公务员是为了权力
But many people become IAS for power.
看
Look
电可以点亮灯泡，给人们的生活带来了光明
power lights the bulb and brings light to the life of people.
而且电也可以电死人
And power can also electrocute and kill people.
你必须决定如何使用权力
You have to decide how to use power.
别管了
Leave it.
告诉我，你为什么想成为一名公务员？
Tell me that why do you want to become an IAS officer?
桑迪普先生，我想为国家服务
Mr. Sandeep, I want to serve the country.
我想为国家做点事
I want to do something for the country.
这是一个非常普遍的答案
This is a very common answer.
每个人都会说同样的话来打动面试官
Everyone says the same the thing to impress mentors.
我也说了同样的话
I also said the same thing.
但是这里有一个问题
There is one problem in this.
每个人都在为国家服务
Everyone is serving the country.
从卖茶人到商人
From the tea seller to the businessman.
从运动员到精神导师
From sportsman to spiritual Guru
农民和纳税人
farmer and tax payer.
- 每个人都要交税-是的，每个人都要交税
- Everyone pays tax. - Yes, everyone pays.
他们也在为国家服务
They are also serving the country.
通过了公务员考试 ，你将如何为国家服务？
How are you going to serve the country by doing IAS?
告诉我
Tell me that.
兄弟，桑迪普，这也是一种服务国家的方式
Brother, Sandeep this is also a way of serving country.
这是一种方式
This is a way.
但是任何其他通过公务员考试的人
But any other person who becomes IAS
也会和你说的一样
would also do the same as you are saying.
为什么要成为公务员？
Why should you become IAS?
你一定有什么特别的地方
There must be something special in you
通过这种方式，你可以比其他公务员做得更好
by which you can do better than others as IAS.
肯定有什么东西
There must be something.
是的
Yes.
你会怎么做? 告诉我
What will you do? Tell me.
你有什么特别的地方？
What special will you do?
事实上我从来没有思考过这些问题
Actually I have never thought about something like this.
想想吧，这就是你需要思考的地方
Think about it. This is where you need to think.
不仅仅是面试官
More than interviewer
你应该清楚为什么你想成为一名公务员
you should be clear as to why you want to become an IAS.
公务员考试不是从国家行政学院开始，而是从准备开始
The training of IAS does not start from LBSNAA but from the preparation
怎么了？
What?
没什么
Nothing.
你的收音机修好了吗？
Did you get your radio repaired?
修好了吗？
Is it repaired?
你要喝水吗？
Will you drink water?
不，兄弟
No, brother.
你学过电子学吗？
Have you studied electronics?
不，我学过电学，但我能做所有这些
No, I have studied electrical but I can do all this.
好的，很好
Okay, that is good.
桑迪普兄弟，你有什么选择？
Brother Sandeep, what is your optional?
你对选修科目感到困惑吗？
Are you confused about the optional?
是的，我正在考虑改变
Yes. I am thinking of changing.
这是你第一次考试吗？
Is this your first attempt?
不，这是最后一次
No. This is last.
- 最后一次?-是的
- Last? - Yes
谁会在最后一次考试中改变了科目？
Who changes the subject in the last attempt?
你之前的科目是什么？
What was your subject earlier?
电学
It was electrical.
经历三次失败，我明白了这一点
By failing three times I have understood that
这不会帮我通过考试的
this is not going to help me to pass.
正确地思考然后决定
Think properly and then decide.
变更科目就像离婚一样
Changing subject is just like taking divorce.
很痛苦
Very painful.
因为这个，我真的很紧张
I am really tensed because of this.
我很清楚我想学历史
I was clear that I want to take History.
但是每个人都把我搞糊涂了，我无法做出决定
But everyone has confused me. I am not able to make a decision.
如果我这次选择了错误的科目，那么一切都完了
If I choose wrong subject this time then everything is over.
告诉我你说错误的科目是什么意思
Tell me what you mean by the wrong subject.
错误的科目？
Wrong subject?
我们得分较低的那个
The one in which we score less marks.
一切似乎都不对劲
Everything seems to be wrong.
我来解释一下
I will explain.
你有女朋友吗？
Do you have a girlfriend?
什么？
What?
白痴，我在问你的女朋友
Idiot, I am asking about your girlfriend.
你为什么感到害羞？
Why are you feeling shy?
女朋友？
Girlfriend?
- 你没有吗?-没有
- Don't you have one? - No.
我喜欢上一份工作中的某个人
I liked someone in my last job.
但一直没有机会和她说话
But never had a chance to talk to her.
我过去常常远远地看着她，她却不知道
I used to look at her from distance. She did not know about it.
真蠢
Stupid.
那是女朋友吗? 别管了
Is that called a girlfriend? Leave it.
这个科目就像是女朋友
The subject is like a girlfriend.
如果你对一个女孩不感兴趣，你怎么会快乐呢？
How can you be happy if you do not have interest in a girl?
你们会分手的
You will break up.
但是你对一个女孩越感兴趣
But the more you are interested in a girl
给她时间，她会给你爱
and give her time she will give you love.
-对吧？-是的
- Right. - Yes.
科目也是如此
Same is with the subject.
想想吧
Think about it.
和优胜者选择同一个主题是无稽之谈
It is nonsense to take the same subject as the topper chose.
或者你在一个特定的科目中得到的分数越来越少
Or you get less or more marks in a particular subject.
如果你学得好，那么你每门课都会得到好成绩
If you have studied well then you will get good marks in every subject.
顶尖考生明白这一点，这就是为什么他们成为优胜者
Toppers understand this so that is why they became toppers.
是的
Yes.
正确
Correct.
你不是唯一一个
You are not the only one.
有许多天才或傻瓜
There were many genius or fools
他们在最后一次尝试中改变了科目，创造了历史
who have changed the subject in the last attempt and have created history.
你也可以创造历史，谁知道呢？
You too can make history. Who knows?
要有信心
Have confidence.
搞定了吗？
- Is it done?
每个人说别人可能通过或不通过都是正常的
Everyone was right in saying that others may pass or not
但你今年一定会通过 UPSC
but you will surely pass the UPSC this year.
我们走着瞧吧
Let's see.
试一下
Take this and check.
- 你修好了吗?-修好了
- Have you repaired it? - Yes, I have done it.
很好
Very good.
你决定选哪个科目了吗？
So have you decided your subject?
是的，历史
Yes, History.
桑迪普兄弟，他是史威特克图
Brother Sandeep, he is Shwet Ketu.
嘿，你可以穿着拖鞋进来
Hey, you can come in with slippers on.
我知道，兄弟
I know it, brother.
好吧
Okay fine.
好吧 桑迪普兄弟
Okay, brother Sandeep.
好，祝你好运，好好学习
Okay. Good luck. Study well.
是的
Yes.
再见
Bye.
桑迪普兄弟..
Brother Sandeep...
不..
No...
- 好的-继续
- Okay. - Carry on.
好了走吧
Okay fine. Let's go.
别再问了
Don't ask again.
他很忙
He is busy.
你在电话里和谁聊天？
Whom are you chatting with on the phone?
我在消除一个学生的疑虑
I was clearing doubt of a student.
一定是个女学生
It must be a female student.
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
又怎么了？
What now?
是你创建了这个群组，‘格里的婚姻’吗？
Did you make this group, 'Guri's Marriage'?
我已经邀请了我们那一批UPSC所有的朋友
I have invited all friends from UPSC batch
还有阿比拉什
and have added Abhilash as well.
你为什么生气？
Why are you getting angry?
只要你向前迈一步，他就会..
If you take a step forward only then he will...
是我的错吗？
Was it my fault?
我说过这是你的错吗？
Did I say it was your fault?
但你也可以表现出你的高贵
But you can show your nobility as well.
你怎么没问过我就创建了一个小组？
How did you make a group without asking me?
你没看过他的视频吗？
Don't you see his videos?
- 视频...-小声点
- Videos... - Talk softly.
但为什么要叫他来参加我的婚礼呢？
But why call him to my wedding?
他傲慢自大，不会回复的
He is arrogant and will not reply.
看看吧
Just see.
他在打字
He is typing.
我非常了解你们两个
I know both of you very well.
我们是儿时的朋友，这不是开玩笑
We are childhood friends and it is not a joke.
虽然这是他的错，但他心地并不坏
He is not bad at heart. Though it was his fault.
看看这个
Look. Look this.
阿比拉什退出了群聊
Abhilash left